

+1 (317) 665 5829

0

Indianapolis, Indiana

ABOUT

I am a professional with over 13 years in marketing and advertising industry. I am an art director and web developer, passionate in using technology and creativity to solve problems. I have bachelors in Graphic Design, studied web development at Eleven Fifty Academy and a recent graduate (developer) of Salesforce and Deloitte Pathfinder program and 60 Trailhead Badges.

WEBSITES, PORTFOLIOS, PROFILES

- Portfolio https://oladelematthew.github.io/oladelematthew-github.io
- Github https://github.com/oladelematthew
- LinkedIn https://www.linkedin.com/in/matthew-oladele

SKILLS

- Proficient in Adobe Creative Suite Photoshop, Illustrator, Indesign, and Premiere
- Proficient in Microsoft Office Word, Powerpoint and Excel
- Proficient in HTML, CSS, Javascript, JSON, REST API's, React, Express.js and Typescript
- Proficient in Run Time Environments (Node.js) and Databases (PostgreSQL, MySQL)
- Intermediate in wordpress

WORK EXPERIENCE

ART DIRECTOR | May 2019 - April 2020

The Bentcil Company - Indianapolis, IN

- Conceptualized and generated 360 campaign for new brand the company wanted to launch to consumers
- Developed new (marketing) ideas to boost sales of promotional products
- Created custom layouts and designs for clients

CREATIVE GROUP HEAD | June 2016 - July 2017 **Saatchi Lagos - Nigeria**

- I was responsible for the quality and pace of delivery of all work leaving the team
- Tasked with the aim of (continuously) raising the bar of art direction within the department and the industry
- Liaised with key internal and external clients contacts with the aim of selling concepts and ideas

TEAM LEAD (ART) | March 2015 - June 2016

X3M Ideas - Lagos, Nigeria

- Worked closely with copywriters to generate creative ideas and concepts to fulfill the client's briefs
- Mentored and trained subordinates within the team to deliver outstanding work at all times at a pace that delights external clients
- My team pitched new ideas to clients, which won us new accounts/clients

ART DIRECTOR | September 2014 - March 2015

X3M Ideas - Lagos, Nigeria

- I was commissioned to plan, design and layout annual reports for the six (6) geopolitical zones in Nigeria.
- Worked with a team that delivered 360 degrees campaign on various accounts

JUNIOR ART DIRECTOR | August 2013 - December 2013

The Jupiter Drawing Room - Cape Town, South Africa

- Understudied art direction and conceptualization from senior art directors and creative heads
- Worked closely with copywriters to generate creative ideas and concepts to fulfill the client's briefs

EDUCATION

Salesforce and Deloitte Pathfinder Program | June 2020 - August 2020

Salesforce Developer (Technical Certification in progress)

- Salesforce and Deloitte joint program to build Salesforce Developer and business soft skills
- Completed 60 Badges, achieved Trailhead Expeditioner rank
- Advanced technical skills include: Apex, Visualforce, CRM, App Logic, App Lifecycle, Security, Integration, Data Management, Database, Lightning

Eleven Fifty Academy (Indianapolis, IN) | February 2020 - July 2020 Web Development Certificate

- Relevant coursework: APIs, DOM, Firebase Deployment, Heroku Deployment, Introduction to Ui, CSS, Express, GIT, GitHub, HTML, Javascript, Node, PostgreSQL, React, Sequelize
- Related Projects: Utilized HTML, CSS, bootstrap, Formspree and Javascript to build a
 personal portfolio. Also created a React App using React framework, React Libraries
 and Node.js

AAA School of Advertising (Cape Town, SA) | July 2013 - November 2013 Professional Diploma, Media Management

- Relevant coursework: Media Strategy, Advertising and Marketing Communications, Creative Thinking
- Related Projects: Developed a full media plan and strategy for clients/agencies

Federal University of Technology (Ondo, Nigeria) | December 2003 - September 2008 Bachelor Degree in Graphic Design

GPA: 3.58

- Relevant coursework: Photography, Illustration, Color Theory, Screen printing, Freehand Drawing, 3D Modelling, Printing, Advertising, Publishing and Book Design, Typography
- Related Projects: Digital Wall Branding of The ETF building of the university

PROJECTS

Personal Portfolio

- https://oladelematthew.github.io/oladelematthew-github.io
- Utilized HTML, CSS, bootstrap, Formspree and JavaScript

React App - taskPriority

- https://om-taskpriority.herokuapp.com
- Frontend was built with React and backend in Node.js

Group Project - Premier Commercial Service

- https://premier-client.herokuapp.com
- Frontend was built with typescript and backend in Node.js

Art Direction / Graphic Design

https://www.behance.net/matthewoladele

VOLUNTEER PROJECTS

FUNetix App

- https://funetix.org/
- The patented, FUNetix 12 Hour Reading App is a "Wonderful Flight to Literacy,"
 "Free to ALL Children," available NOW to stream on any laptop or desktop
 computer.

DESCENDANTS OF GODS

- https://www.behance.net/gallery/93909549/DESCENDANTS-OF-GODS
- I collaborated with Eleven (an advertising agency in California) to create Black History Month 2020 Campaign